<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Things I Want My Kids to Know - A Father's Advice</title>
    <description>Scott Johnson writing things for his kids.   They won't listen but I'm still going to try.
</description>
    <link>https://fuzzyblog.io/tiwmktk/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://fuzzyblog.io/tiwmktk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 09:16:22 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 09:16:22 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Twelve Rules for Your First Job</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My eldest son just got his first job (ok his second job but this is the first one that counts). He is in a customer facing service technician role and this is the advice that I wish had been given to me when I got my first job:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never swear at least where a customer can hear.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be respectful to your boss.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google your boss before you start; information is power.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be on time; be early if you can.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be prepared.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work hard.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be kind to customers; be even kinder to your co workers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dress fitting the needs of the job.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be humble with your coworkers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accept responsibility when you make a mistake.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pay attention and notice things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nothing can ever be too clean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few clarifications:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My first job was working for the family business and I remember, 39 years later, my Dad dressing me down when I swore in front of a customer (mind you I was maybe 12 and struggling to load a 70 plus pound bucket of drive way sealer into the trunk of their car without any help; no matter, I was &lt;strong&gt;absolutely in the wrong&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customers come and go but your coworkers are there day in and day out; being kind to customers but rotten to your coworkers will hurt you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dress is something that is highly tied to the job.  If you work in front of a customer, neat and clean is generally the rule but it varies widely – if you work in an adult bookstore, for example, cleavage is the rule not the exception.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paying attention in work (and in life) really, really matters.  If you make a conscious effort to notice things, you’ll be amazed at what you can learn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In terms of things never being too clean, if you really want to impress your boss, make a concerted effort to keep things clean.  Trust me – your boss will notice; they always notice this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 09:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://fuzzyblog.io/tiwmktk/work/2019/09/07/so-you-got-your-first-job.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fuzzyblog.io/tiwmktk/work/2019/09/07/so-you-got-your-first-job.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
